<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Chez Nosredna]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Chez Nosredna Cookbook]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 16:39:48 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Tuna Moosh]]></title><description><![CDATA[You’re smart people, you can figure it out. The can of tuna image is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.…]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io/tuna-moosh/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://alpinegizmo.github.io/tuna-moosh/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 11:57:30 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You’re smart people, you can figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The can of tuna image is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported license.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[No Knead Bread]]></title><description><![CDATA[The ur-recipe that created a cult: The internet is full of recipes for no-knead bread. This one from jocooks.com is another good starting…]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io/bread/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://alpinegizmo.github.io/bread/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 11:08:01 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The ur-recipe that created a cult:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 56.25%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.0725rem&quot; &gt; &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/13Ah9ES2yTU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen style=&quot; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; &quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet is full of recipes for no-knead bread. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jocooks.com/recipes/no-knead-bread/&quot;&gt;This one from jocooks.com&lt;/a&gt; is another good starting point, but doesn’t include a second rise, which is something you want. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chowhound.com/post/knead-bread-rise-344524?page=2&quot;&gt;What does the second rise do?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasoning behind no-knead bread is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By using very little yeast, a lot of water, and a long rising time, you’re getting a lot of fermentation and gluten development (that otherwise requires kneading).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By baking it in a closed dutch oven, all that water in the dough is creating steam, which mimicks the steam ovens that bakers use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve found these factors are helpful in getting good results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During the initial mixing, be sure to be thorough. It’s not that you have to work the dough, but any flour that doesn’t get wet now will become a regret later on. You can just leave it in the bowl you mixed it in, covered with plastic wrap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t skimp on the rising time. Plan on 16-18 hours for the first rise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before you turn on the oven, take the dough and do a few stretch/fold maneuvers (and don’t worry if it’s a shaggy blob). This involves stretching the dough out in one dimension, enough to then fold it over in thirds. Then rotate 90°, and repeat. Do about four of these stretches and folds, and then shape and pinch the blob into a loaf as best you can, putting the seam down onto parchment paper. Cover again and let it rest for about two hours. I’ve found covering it with a towel makes a mess, so I suggest transfering it back into the mixing bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With both of these rises, it’s not really about waiting for a preset about of time, but rather waiting until the dough has reached the right stage of readiness. You’ll learn to recognize this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pre-heat the oven to 450°F (around 230°C), with the dutch oven in the oven (which is why you didn’t put the shaggy blob into the dutch oven earlier — you’d rather not have to move it an extra time). You can start this about 30 minutes before the second rise is done, as it will take your oven a while to heat up. (Part of what’s happening during this second rise is that the blob is developing a tougher “skin” that will hold the loaf together, and allow the gas inside to expand, while holding it in.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When it’s time to bake, you’ll have to &lt;em&gt;carefully&lt;/em&gt; take the hot dutch oven out of the oven.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use the parchment paper to lift the proto-loaf and ferry it into the dutch oven like a helicopter. But you’ll probably want to reshape it somewhat first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you take the lid off after the first 30 minutes of baking, you can remove the parchment paper, if you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slash the loaf with a knife before baking. This isn’t just about making it pretty — it reduces the surface tension of the loaf, and helps it open up while baking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rye Tahini Chocolate Cookies]]></title><description><![CDATA[Based on the recipes from Green Kitchen Stories and The Boy Who Bakes. Step 1 Combine the flours, baking powder, and salt. Step 2 Mix the…]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io/rye-tahini-chocolate-cookies/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://alpinegizmo.github.io/rye-tahini-chocolate-cookies/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 10:13:49 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Based on the recipes from &lt;a href=&quot;https://greenkitchenstories.com/tahini-rye-cookies/&quot;&gt;Green Kitchen Stories&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theboywhobakes.co.uk/recipes/2019/3/7/tahini-and-rye-chocolate-chip-cookies-inspired-by-mokonuts-in-paris&quot;&gt;The Boy Who Bakes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combine the flours, baking powder, and salt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mix the butter, tahini, sugar, and dates (if desired) in a food processor until light and fluffy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 3&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the eggs (in the food processor).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mix the wet into the dry, add the chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 5&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refrigerate until firm (~2 hours).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 6&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to 190°C / 380°F, or a bit cooler (170°C) with the fan. (Yes, this is a bit hotter than normal for cookies.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roll dough into balls, and coat them with sesame seeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bake for 10-11 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After they’ve been in the oven for 6-7 minutes, remove the tray from the oven and smack it against the countertop a few times to help the cookies flatten out a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bake until slightly browned.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Buttermilk Pancakes]]></title><description><![CDATA[Based on the recipe in The Joy of Cooking (which we received two copies of as wedding presents). Yields 10-12 large pancakes. This recipe…]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io/pancakes/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://alpinegizmo.github.io/pancakes/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 09:12:43 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Based on the recipe in &lt;em&gt;The Joy of Cooking&lt;/em&gt; (which we received two copies of as wedding presents). Yields 10-12 large pancakes. This recipe scales up and down reasonably well (if you cut the recipe in half, the extra egg isn’t a problem).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whisk together the dry ingredients, then add the wet to the dry. Do not overwork the batter; you don’t want to develop the gluten. Don’t worry about having some lumps, they’ll disappear during cooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The popular notion that “the first pancake is always spoiled” is only true if you aren’t familiar with the pan and the stove. Once you know what you’re doing, you can get it right every time. Just make sure the pan is hot before you pour on the batter. A droplet of water should skeeter across the pan: if it sits there, the pan is too cold, if it evaporates instantly, it’s too hot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For miso maple butter, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.myrecipes.com/extracrispy/miso-maple-butter-recipe&quot;&gt;Miso Maple Butter Is the Condiment You Have Been Missing Your Entire Life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Variations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Yamcakes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microwave a yam while mixing up the batter. Moosh up half of the yam (unless it’s rather small), and add that to the batter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Oatmeal&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replace ½ cup of flour with 1 cup of oatmeal. If you’re using whole oats, soak them in the buttermilk first, preferably overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Blueberries&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer to place the blueberries into each pancake by hand right after pouring out the batter, especially if the berries are frozen. But you can mix them into the batter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Whole wheat flour&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t replace all of the white flour with whole wheat, use a mixture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same goes for masa; it’s good in pancakes, but keep some of the regular flour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spelt flour is great, but you won’t really notice the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Buckwheat?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, don’t care for it. Didn’t like rye flour either, the one time we tried it.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bibimbap]]></title><description><![CDATA[If you want to take this up a notch, buy a set of dolsot (the traditional stone bowls used for bibimbap) and learn to use them. Ideally a…]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io/bibimbap/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://alpinegizmo.github.io/bibimbap/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 20:28:30 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;If you want to take this up a notch, buy a set of dolsot (the traditional stone bowls used for bibimbap) and learn to use them. Ideally a dolsot bibimbap is served sizzling hot, with the rice crispy and stuck to the bowl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspiration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mykoreankitchen.com/bibimbap-korean-mixed-rice-with-meat-and-assorted-vegetables/&quot;&gt;https://mykoreankitchen.com/bibimbap-korean-mixed-rice-with-meat-and-assorted-vegetables/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://food52.com/recipes/81402-skillet-bibimbap-recipe&quot;&gt;https://food52.com/recipes/81402-skillet-bibimbap-recipe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.maangchi.com/recipe/bibimbap&quot;&gt;https://www.maangchi.com/recipe/bibimbap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepare some steamed rice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose your protein and vegetables. Aim for a variety of textures and colors; think about how they will look together in the bowl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Variation: pickle some thinly sliced radishes in sugar, vinegar, salt and pepper. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 3&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mix the sauce ingredients in a bowl. Note: different recipes use different ratios of these ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cook the protein and each of the vegetables, keeping everything separate. Season according to taste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a very large pan or skillet, you should find it’s possible (but tricky) to sauté several things in it simultaneously, without mixing them. Or you can use more than one pan, or cook things one at a time. If all this separate cooking sounds annoying, then opt for some veggies that don’t need to be cooked, or that go really fast, like bean sprouts and pickled radishes. (You could just soak the bean sprouts in some boiling water for 1-2 minutes.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 5&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fry the eggs, keeping the yolks runny. (Traditional bibimbap is often served with a raw egg.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Alternative #1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assemble each bowl: rice first, then arrange the protein and vegetables, and top with a fried egg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Alternative #2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assemble everything in a small cast iron skillet, similar to what one would do with the traditional stone bowls, and toast the rice for about 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Final step&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Top with a generous sprinkling of roasted sesame seeds and/or some crushed roasted seaweed, and serve with the sauce on the side.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Norwegian Rice Waffles]]></title><description><![CDATA[If you make some extra rice for dinner the night before, then this comes together quickly. If you didn’t, add in some extra prep time for…]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io/rice-waffles/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://alpinegizmo.github.io/rice-waffles/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 19:57:30 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;If you make some extra rice for dinner the night before, then this comes together quickly. If you didn’t, add in some extra prep time for making the rice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the rice is hot, be careful not to add the eggs directly to the hot rice, or you risk cooking the eggs prematurely (in the mixing bowl).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A belgian waffle iron works fine, but we prefer the texture that results from using a more traditional waffle iron (the thinner waffles have more surface area).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Szechuan Green Beans]]></title><description><![CDATA[Adapted from Microwave Gourmet by Barbara Kafka, 1987, page 293. Step 1 Combine garlic, ginger, and scallions in a food processor. Put into…]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io/szechuan-green-beans/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://alpinegizmo.github.io/szechuan-green-beans/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 18:22:30 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Adapted from &lt;em&gt;Microwave Gourmet&lt;/em&gt; by Barbara Kafka, 1987, page 293.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combine garlic, ginger, and scallions in a food processor. Put into a large microwave safe bowl or casserole dish, add oil and pepper flakes. Microwave uncovered for 3 minutes at 100%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stir in remaining ingredients (soy sauce, rice wine vineger, green beans). Microwave uncovered for 15 minutes at 100%, stopping every 3-4 minutes to stir.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Slow-Roasted Gochujang Chicken]]></title><description><![CDATA[Adapted from https://www.bonappetit.com/recipe/slow-roast-gochujang-chicken. Modifications: I use half as much garlic, add more veggies, and…]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io/gochujang-chicken/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://alpinegizmo.github.io/gochujang-chicken/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 16:20:36 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Adapted from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bonappetit.com/recipe/slow-roast-gochujang-chicken&quot;&gt;https://www.bonappetit.com/recipe/slow-roast-gochujang-chicken&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modifications: I use half as much garlic, add more veggies, and skip the honey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prehead oven to 300° with rack in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season bird with salt and pepper, including inside the cavity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whisk together the gochujang and ¼ cup of olive oil. Grate or mince a couple of garlic cloves, and add that to the gochujang oil. Do the same with the ginger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 3&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cut what’s left of the head of garlic in half, and put one half of it inside the bird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow coat the chicken with roughly half of the gochujang oil. If you have a pastry brush, this is a good time to use it. Reserve some of the gochujang oil to put on the veggies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 5&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decide if you want more than just potatoes: adding a carrot or two, and/or some onion, is a fine thing. Roughly chop the carrot(s), onion, and potatoes if they’re too large, and add in the remaining garlic. Then coat all these veggies with a mixture of the remaining gochujang oil, plus the extra 2 Tbsp of oil. Season with some salt and pepper, give it all a toss to combine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 6&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange the veggies around the outside of your skillet, and plop the chicken down in the middle, right on top of the garlic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 7&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slow-roast this util the potatoes are really tender and the chicken skin is a deep reddish-golden brown, 2½-3 hours. You might want to turn the potatoes and other veggies once or twice so they are nicely coated in the oily juices that will accumulate in the pan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it’s done, the legs should be loose, and the chicken should basically fall apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once out of the oven, let everything rest for 10-15 minutes before cutting into the chicken. This will keep the juices in the meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 8&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scallions, limes, and honey are for dressing things up, if you want. We usually skip the honey, and never have enough scallions.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Papas Chorreadas]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is one of those dishes where you can get away with starting the cooking while you finish the prep. Adapted from The New Laurel’s…]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io/papas-chorreadas/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://alpinegizmo.github.io/papas-chorreadas/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 14:04:36 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is one of those dishes where you can get away with starting the cooking while you finish the prep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adapted from &lt;em&gt;The New Laurel’s Kitchen&lt;/em&gt; by Laurel Robertson, etal, 1986, page 209.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peel the potatoes, or not. Get them going in the microwave while you prep the green beans. Or steam the potatoes on the stove until just barely done. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sauté the onion in the olive oil until tender, then add the garlic, green onions, chili, and aromatics. (The original recipe calls for butter rather than olive oil. Ehh.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 3&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the tomatoes and salt, and give everything a nice stir from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point the potatoes will be done, and you can switch to steaming the green beans in the microwave (if you didn’t steam both veggies on the stove). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the potatoes and green beans to the skillet as they become ready. Mash the potatoes into the mixture, get it nice and smooshy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let everything cook together for 5-10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 5&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want the creamy goopiness, add it just before serving.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>