<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Chez Nosredna]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Chez Nosredna Cookbook]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 20:17:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Norwegian Rice Waffles]]></title><description><![CDATA[If you make some extra rice for dinner the night before, then this comes together quickly. If the rice is hot, be careful not to add the…]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io/rice-waffles/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://alpinegizmo.github.io/rice-waffles/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 19:57:30 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;If you make some extra rice for dinner the night before, then this comes together quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the rice is hot, be careful not to add the eggs directly to the hot rice, or you risk cooking the eggs prematurely (in the mixing bowl).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Szechuan Green Beans]]></title><description><![CDATA[Adapted from Microwave Gourmet by Barbara Kafka, 1987, page 293. Step 1 Combine garlic, ginger, and scallions in a food processor. Put into…]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io/szechuan-green-beans/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://alpinegizmo.github.io/szechuan-green-beans/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 18:22:30 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Adapted from &lt;em&gt;Microwave Gourmet&lt;/em&gt; by Barbara Kafka, 1987, page 293.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combine garlic, ginger, and scallions in a food processor. Put into a large microwave safe bowl or casserole dish, add oil and pepper flakes. Microwave uncovered for 3 minutes at 100%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stir in remaining ingredients (soy sauce, rice wine vineger, green beans). Microwave uncovered for 15 minutes at 100%, stopping every 3-4 minutes to stir.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Slow-Roasted Gochujang Chicken]]></title><description><![CDATA[Adapted from https://www.bonappetit.com/recipe/slow-roast-gochujang-chicken. Step 1 Prehead oven to 300° with rack in the middle. Season…]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io/gochujang-chicken/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://alpinegizmo.github.io/gochujang-chicken/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 16:20:36 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Adapted from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bonappetit.com/recipe/slow-roast-gochujang-chicken&quot;&gt;https://www.bonappetit.com/recipe/slow-roast-gochujang-chicken&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prehead oven to 300° with rack in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season bird with salt and pepper, including inside the cavity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whisk together the gochujang and ¼ cup of olive oil. Grate or mince a couple of garlic cloves, and add that to the gochujang oil. Do the same with the ginger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 3&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cut what’s left of the head of garlic in half, and put one half of it inside the bird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow coat the chicken with roughly half of the gochujang oil. If you have a pastry brush, this is a good time to use it. Reserve some of the gochujang oil to put on the veggies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 5&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decide if you want more than just potatoes: adding a carrot or two, and/or some onion, is a fine thing. Roughly chop the carrot(s), onion, and potatoes if they’re too large, and add in the remaining garlic. Then coat all these veggies with a mixture of the remaining gochujang oil, plus the extra 2 Tbsp of oil. Season with some salt and pepper, give it all a toss to combine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 6&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange the veggies around the outside of your skillet, and plop the chicken down in the middle, right on top of the garlic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 7&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slow-roast this util the potatoes are really tender and the chicken skin is a deep reddish-golden brown, 2½-3 hours. You might want to turn the potatoes and other veggies once or twice so they are nicely coated in the oily juices that will accumulate in the pan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it’s done, the legs should be loose, and the chicken should basically fall apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once out of the oven, let everything rest for 10-15 minutes before cutting into the chicken. This will keep the juices in the meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 8&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scallions, limes, and honey are for dressing things up, if you want. We usually skip the honey, and never have enough scallions.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Papas Chorreadas]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is one of those dishes where you can get away with starting the cooking while you finish the prep. Adapted from The New Laurel’s…]]></description><link>https://alpinegizmo.github.io/papas-chorreadas/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://alpinegizmo.github.io/papas-chorreadas/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 14:04:36 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is one of those dishes where you can get away with starting the cooking while you finish the prep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adapted from &lt;em&gt;The New Laurel’s Kitchen&lt;/em&gt; by Laurel Robertson, etal, 1986, page 209.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peel the potatoes, or not. Get them going in the microwave while you prep the green beans. Or steam the potatoes on the stove until just barely done. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sauté the onion in the olive oil until tender, then add the garlic, green onions, chili, and aromatics. (The original recipe calls for butter rather than olive oil. Ehh.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 3&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the tomatoes and salt, and give everything a nice stir from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point the potatoes will be done, and you can switch to steaming the green beans in the microwave (if you didn’t steam both veggies on the stove). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the potatoes and green beans to the skillet as they become ready. Mash the potatoes into the mixture, get it nice and smooshy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let everything cook together for 5-10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 5&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want the creamy goopiness, add it just before serving.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>